



Daniele Giardiello

Date of birth: 28/11/1988 | Nationality: Italian | Gender: Male |

(+39) 3476731205 | daniele.giardiello1@gmail.com

https://danielegiardiello.github.io/ | Italy

About me:

Statistician | Data scientist with robust experience in research and statistical consulting in various international research institutes and private companies. R / SAS / STATA / Python programmer with strong passion in data science and statistics. Extremely curious to actively know new skills through challenging learning and working in team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/04/2021 - 30/09/2022 - Bolzano/Bozen, Italy

BIOMEDICAL DATA SCIENTIST / BIOSTATISTICIAN (HOME-BASED) - EURAC RESEARCH

Biomedical data scientist and statistical consultant in the field of biomedical research.

Research topics: epidemiology of COVID-19, causal inference techniques such as Mendelian Randomization, and causal risk prediction modelling.

Website https://www.eurac.edu/en

15/11/2016 - 28/02/2021 - Amsterdam, Netherlands

PHD CANDIDATE - THE NETHERLANDS CANCER INSTITUTE (NKI)

Main goal: to develop, validate and assess the prediction performance and the clinical utility of a contralateral breast cancer risk prediction model using time-to-event models with competing risks using individual patient data (more than 100,000 patients) from multiple studies in presence of sporadic and systematic missing data.

Main activities:

- Data management and R/SAS/STATA programming also using High Performance Computing (HPC);
- Experience in Real World Data coming from different international sources;
- Statistical consulting for researchers and statistical teaching;
- Provide statistical reports using Rmarkdown and GitHub.

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities | **Department** Molecular Pathology |

Address Netherlands | Website https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/schmidt-m-group/

01/07/2016 – 30/09/2016 – Desio, Italy

STATISTICIAN - OPIS SRL

Overall description: biostatistician working in clinical trials (phase II-III).

Main activities:

SAS programming; Revising Case Report Forms (CRFs); Providing listings, figures, and tables.

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities

Address 20832 , Desio (Monza and Brianza), Italy | Website https://opisresearch.com/

STATISTICIAN - ITALIAN NATIONAL CANCER INSTITUTE

- Statistical consulting in medical research;
- R/SAS programming;
- Supporting research in statistical medical writing;

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities

Department Clinical Epidemiology and Clinical Trials organization | **Address** 20133, Milan, Italy

Website https://www.istitutotumori.mi.it/en/home

04/2013 - 09/2014 - Brescia, Italy

STATISTICIAN - THE LOMBARDY AND EMILIA ROMAGNA EXPERIMENTAL ZOOTECHNIC INSTITUTE

- Statistical consulting and support for veterinary research;
- Epidemiological surveillance;
- Spatial statistics;

Business or Sector Professional, scientific and technical activities | **Address** 25124, Brescia, Italy

Website https://www.izsler.it/

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/11/2016 - 28/02/2021 - Leiden, Netherlands

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY, PHD - Leiden University

My dissertation is available here

Address Leiden, Netherlands

Website https://scholarlypublications.universiteitleiden.nl/handle/1887/3455362

Thesis Title of the dissertation: "Prediction of contralateral breast cancer - Statistical aspects and performance assessment"

10/2010 - 11/2012 - Milan, Italy

MSC IN BIOSTATISTICS AND EXPERIMENTAL STATISTICS (SUMMA CUM LAUDE) – University of Milan - Bicocca

Address Milan, Italy | Website https://en.unimib.it/

10/2007 - 09/2010 - Milan, Italy

BSC IN STATISTICAL SCIENCE AND INFORMATION MANAGEMENT (SUMMA CUM LAUDE) – Univ ersity of Milan - Bicocca

Address Milan, Italy | Website https://en.unimib.it/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ITALIAN**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
DUTCH	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

R | SAS | STATA | SPSS software | SQL | R Markdown | GitHUB | Python

PUBLICATIONS

List of all publications in pubmed

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=daniele+giardiello&sort=date&size=100

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Hobbies and interests

Running (middle-distance track and field athlete), nature, music, hospital clowning